#### +65 92465603 📞

# matias.quintana@sec.ethz.ch ☑

matiasquintana.com/ 🌐

github.com/matgr 🦪

linkedin.com/in/matiasqr/ in

# MATIAS QUINTANA

# DATA SCIENCE RESEARCH FELLOW AND PROJECT MANAGER

#### SUMMARY

More than 8 years of experience in developing machine learning solutions and internet of things with +5 years of expertise in sustainability. Experienced in leading international teams as well as private and government stakeholder management.

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Postdoctoral Researcher & Module Coordinator** *Singapore-ETH Centre, ETH Zürich* Apr 2023 – Present

- Led and managed team of 6 researchers (Postdocs, Ph.D. students, software developers) across Singapore and Zurich on an SGD1M project.
- Performed deep learning research for smart cities applications.
- Collaborated with government agencies and industry partners for Al-based solutions at the urban scale.

Postdoctoral Research Fellow National University of Singapore (NUS)

Aug 2022 - Mar 2023

- Led and managed research projects in machine learning while mentoring 1
  M.Sc and 3 Ph.D. students.
- Taught Data Science and Al graduate and undergraduate modules.
- Gave workshops to local and international students and research groups.

**Graduate Research Assistant** National University of Singapore (NUS)

Aug 2018 - Aug 2022

- Performed unsupervised and semi-supervised learning research on Building Energy data, while mentoring 11 B.Sc and 1 M.Sc. students.
- Published 26 peer-reviewed papers and presented at intl. conferences
- Created content and assignments for Data Science MOOC (Finalist Innovation in Online Teaching)

Firmware & Mobile Developer VIT Initiative, LLC

Dec 2017 - Jun 2018

- Designed and pitched wearable product at clients' site and funding events.
- Designed and developed mobile application for wearable products.

**Graduate Research Assistant** Carnegie Mellon University (CMU)

Apr 2017 – Jun 2018

- Collaborated in Government funded project about Building Energy Efficiency.
- Designed, built, and programmed an AC waveform power meter.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Singapore-ETH Centre | Led ML and science communication workshops
- Office of Student Affairs, NUS
  Resident Assistant and Secretary
- Latino Graduate Student Association, CMU | President

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Ph.D. Engineering

National University of Singapore (NUS)

Aug 2018 - Nov 2022

## Master of Information Systems Management

Carnegie Mellon University (CMU)

Aug 2015 - Dec 2016

# **BSc. Electronic Engineering**

Pontifical Catholic University of Peru

Mar 2009 - Jul 2014

#### PROGRAMMING

Python

Bash

SQL

**JAVA** 

R

**MATLAB** 

#### TOOLS

Git

**AWS** 

MLOps

Hardware prototyping

#### LANGUAGES

Spanish

English

French (Basic)

Mandarin (Basic)

#### HOBBIES

Weightlifting

Running

Salsa and bachata dancing

Playing string instruments

Photography